NICK HVATTUM

Monroe, WA • (425) 791-4452 • NHvattum@gmail.com

Full Stack Web Developer

Summary

I am a Software Engineer motivated by utilizing my background in QA to achieve practical, precise solutions to technical problems. I enjoy using my unique background along with my technical skills to create software that will impact the life of the end user

Web Development Experience

May 2020 - Aug. 2020

Software Engineering Immersive Student

General Assembly, Remote

Full-time, full-stack software engineering program that provided 500 hours of training in 13 weeks. Included 4 projects utilizing the latest front and back-end programming languages, tools, and practices including:

• ExpressJS • Python • UX Design • Git • Github • RESTful Routing • TypeScript

First-place Winning Hackathon Project:

https://insplore.vercel.app/

Completed Projects:

https://stay-inside.netlify.app/ https://mix-it-up-nh.herokuapp.com/auth/login https://nhvattum.github.io/Social-Distancing/

Work Experience

Aug. 2019 - Mar. 2020

Laboratory Quality Control Technician

Western Pneumatic Tube Company, Kirkland, WA

- Improved time required to perform product integrity tests
- Integrated test data into a central database to improve ease of access
- Streamlined communication between the testing lab and manufacturing supervisors in order to improve manufacturing time
- \cdot Ensured all findings met state and federal specifications as well as the customer's requirements
- Created and performed R&D tests to determine best manufacturing practices

Jan. 2017 - Aug. 2019

Medical Coder, HIM Clerk, Health Unit Coordinator, Program Specialist

Fairfax Behavioral Health, Kirkland, WA

- · Implemented new organizational system that improved both accuracy and speed of documentation completion
- · Created individualized plans for providers to complete documentation in a timely manner
- \cdot Analyzed patient charts and applied any applicable medical codes in various computer programs with a level of precision that improved the hospital's overall accuracy
- Reviewed charts for audits to improve and ensure documentation accuracy for the facility
- Coordinated both internally and outside the facility to improve the time taken to deliver all necessary documentation

Dec. 2014 - Dec. 2016

Restaurant Manager

Artisan Foodworks, Monroe, WA

- · Supervised a team of 10+ employees, focusing on each person's strengths in order to improve ticket time
- Created a more cohesive team environment by implementing new communication processes between front and back of house employees

- · Trained new employees
- Resolved customer service issues
- · Responsible for handling money and closing out the till

2008 - 2011 Humanitarian Aid- Volunteer

Haiti

Provided humanitarian aid and disaster relief over 5 separate trips both before and after the 2010 earthquake

- Provided a clean source of water and delivered food
- Built the first school in a large community
- · Built houses
- Built and worked in a field hospital
- ${\boldsymbol \cdot}$ Established a day-camp for for displaced kids post-earthquake

Education

May 2020 - Aug. 2020 Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly

 $Full-time\ software\ engineering\ program\ which\ includes\ various\ technologies\ in\ both\ front-end\ and\ back-end$

developing

2015 - 2018 Associate's of Arts and Sciences

Everett Community College

Certifications

Received Aug. 2020 Software Engineering Immersive Certificate of Completion

General Assembly

Received Dec. 2018 CPC-A (Certified Professional Coder through AAPC)

Medisense